
*****************************************************************************
                               Reflection
                             Workshop - #4
Full Name  : Elmar Jafarli
Student ID#: 162895221
Email      : ejafarli@myseneca.ca
Section    : ZCC

Authenticity Declaration:
I declare this submission is the result of my own work and has not been
shared with any other student or 3rd party content provider. This submitted
piece of work is entirely of my own creation.
*****************************************************************************

1. Programming relies heavily on selection because it enables the program to make decisions and apply logic to statements. Without the utilization of choice, projects will just can run from one finish to the next without having the option to execute a bunch of elective groupings.
Examples: 
I.I used an "if" statement to determine whether the user is entering fewer, more, or the same number of groceries as they had previously selected. I was able to carry out specific operations with the help of an if statement when a particular condition was satisfied.
II. I checked additional conditions related to the user's selected grocery options by employing an "else if" statement immediately following the "if" statement. I was able to carry out the specific operations that were supposed to be carried out when a particular condition other than that in the "if" block was met thanks to this.
III. A third "else if" statement was also used to see if the conditions for exiting the loop had been met. I was able to specify a condition that caused the loop to end when it was true thanks to this.

2. One logic construct is enclosed within another in a construct known as a nested construct. Crosswords are like nested constructs. To begin, you access the first row and iterate through all of its columns. After that, you move to the second row and iterate through each column there. After that, you move on to the third row, and so on. I have nested multiple while loops into a single while loop during the workshop.
The single while loop cycles through each fruit until the user enters a zero to stop the loop. However, while loops are also present in the fruits. In order to prevent incorrect input, each fruit has its own while loop. As a result, a number of while loops are contained within the larger while loop. A nested construct is the term for this.

3. The "while loop" iteration construct is my favorite. Based on a given Boolean condition, a while loop lets code run repeatedly. Consider the while loop to be an iterative if statement. The code is executed until a condition becomes false. Similar to the while loop, the "do while loop" is rarely used because the way it works is typically not required by the majority of programs. The "while loop" is inferior to the "for loop." The "For loop" is very simple to use and gives you a lot more control. In contrast to a while loop, you can easily specify the start, end, and increment/decrement in a for loop. The only drawback is that, in contrast to "while" loops, "for" loops do not function when a Boolean condition is used to run the entire loop.
In my assignment, I have used a while loop multiple times.
For instance) Section 2 sudden spikes in demand for a solitary "while" circle (with numerous settled "while" circles) which expresses that the circle would be left on the off chance that the client squeezes "0" in a particular brief. Nonetheless, in the event that the client enters "1" rather than a zero, the circle continues to run. A "for" loop couldn't be used very well in this case because, unlike a "while" loop, one would have to specify the number of iterations beforehand. A "do-while" circle is likewise not liked in this situation.
